Guide to the Harry Gamboa Jr. Papers, 1968-1995
Department of Special Collections
- Series X: Slide Listing
  - NO DETOUR, 1993fotonovela which was then put into video format (included in Stanford collection), performed by Maria Elena Chavez and Octavio Tizoc Gaitan-Diaz. Presented before a live audience at the Robert Flahert Seminar, NY. (Box 13, Folder 127)
  - HECHO EN LATINOAMERICA, 1978installation shot of Gamboa photo work exhibited at Museo de Arte Moderno (Mexico). (Box 13, Folder 128)
  - CONNECTIONS II, 1994installation shot of Gamboa mixed media work exhibited at the Getty Center for the History of Art the Humanities. (Box 13, Folder 129)
  - Milagro Mirage, 1994mixed media installation from solo exhibit THE URBAN DESERT by Gamboa. (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - Concrete Storm (foreground) mixed media installation from solo exhibit THE URBAN DESERT. (Box 13, Folder 131)
  - 100 Alibis, 1994text (included in Stanford collection) installation, from solo exhibit THE URBAN DESERT. (Box 13, Folder 132)
  - Dia de los Muertos celebrant. ELA, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 133)
  - Two boys, L.A., 1973 (Box 13, Folder 134)
  - UFW protester, L.A. 1979 (Box 13, Folder 135)
  - Old woman in black scarf, L.A., 1974 (Box 13, Folder 136)
  - CASA rally-, ELA, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 137)
  - Boy working, ELA, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 138)
  - Boys, ELA, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 139)
  - Children. ELA, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 140)
  - Jr. High School Students, L.A., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 141)
  - Paul Arevalo's tattoo idolizing LOS ILLEGALS band, L.A., 1983 (Box 13, Folder 142)
  - Workers, L.A., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - Children. ELA, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 144)
  - Under arrest at ASCOZILLA exhibit reception, CSULA, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 145)
  - Student protest, Pierce College, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - UFW demonstrators, L.A., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Pedestrian, L.A., 1987 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Homegirls. ELA, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Homeboys. L.A., 1984 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Crowd, L.A., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Vaqueros, Redlands, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - Children dancing, ELA, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - Protester, ELA, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - America Tropical mural by Siqueiros, L.A., 1973 (Box 13, Folder 155-156)
  - May Mass, ELA, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 157)
  - Dancing in backyard wedding reception, ELA, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 158)
  - Girls laughing in crowd, L.A., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 159)
  - Dia de los Muertos children, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 160)
  - Children. ELA, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 161)
  - Homeboy, ELA, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 162)
  - Boy in hat with orange, ELA, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 163)
  - Childrens art. ELA, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 164)
  - Brown Beret, ELA, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Cesar Chavez/UFW rally, L.A., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - AZTLAN, ELA, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Midnight Classics. ELA, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Mask wrestlers employed for sales gimmick, ELA, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Old man in hat. L.A., 1972 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Child looking outside. ELA, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Hanging out with the guys, ELA, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - Ruben Treio, artist (Spokane Falls, WA-based). L.A., 1990 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Dr. Eloy Rodriguez (formerly @ UCI, presently [1995] @ Cornell), San Antonio, TX. 1992 (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Raul Ruiz, (at the time of this image, editor of LA RAZA, currently 1995] @ CSU Northridge), ELA, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - John Valadez, artist, during reception at Victor's Clothing in downtown L.A. for unveil of his interior mural. BROADWAY, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - Rene Yañez, artist, San Francisco, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 177)
  - (l-r) Gloria Alvarez (poet), Yreina-Cervantez.(painter), and Frances Salome Espanña (video artist). L.A., 1991 (Box 13, Folder 178)
  - Rupert Garcia, artist. at home/studio in San Francisco, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 179)
  - Tomas Sanchez, author. L.A., 1981 (Box 13, Folder 180)
  - Cesar Chavez, arriving at CSULA for UFW rally, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 181-182)
  - Leo Limon, artist, L.A., 1990 (Box 13, Folder 183)
  - Mural by Roberto Chavez (building demolished), ELA. 1972 (Box 13, Folder 184)
  - (far right) Jesus Treviño, film/TV director, L.A.. 1978 (Box 13, Folder 185)
  - (l-r) Francisco Gonzalez and David Hidalgo, musicians (original members of LOS LOBOS). ELA, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 186)
  - (l-r) Herbert Siguenza. Richard Montoya, and Ric Salinas, a.k.a.,CULTURE CLASH L.A., 1990 (Box 13, Folder 187)
  - Bert Corona. ELA, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 188)
  - Congressman Edward R. Roybal, L.A., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 189)
  - Joan Baez, at UFW protest March. Modesto. CA., 1974 (Box 13, Folder 190)
  - Barbara Carrasco, artist, with her mural, L.A. HISTORY--A MEXICAN PERSPECTIVE (16' x 80') during a 3 week display at Union Station, as part of L.A. FESTIVAL (mural remains in storage since early 80's. See AZTLAN: MURAL AUSENTE DE BARBARA CARRASCO, LA OPINION. in Stanford collection). L.A., 1990 (Box 13, Folder 191)
  - (l-r) Ralph Cordova (performance artist) and Robert Buitron (photographer), (correspondence in Stanford collection), Phoenix, AZ, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 192)
  - These are actual production slides utilized in slide installation, ANGST FOR THE MEMORIES, in the solo exhibit THE URBAN DESERT, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 193-252)
    WARNING: NO SKIN CONTACT TO SLIDES #193-#252. THESE SLIDES HAVE BEEN TINTED WITH A PURPLE INK WHICH MAY RUIN CLOTHING, PAPER, AND MAY DISCOLOR SKIN. If handled properly, these slides suitable for projection.
- Series XI: Audio Tape Listing
  All audio tapes recorded with nr Dolby "C"
  - Audio Tape 1
    - Vocal track for fotonovela "IN-CITY-ISH", performed by Armando Norte and Consuelo F. Norte. Written by Gamboa. Originally presented at HISPANIC URBAN CENTER, L.A., 19834 min, 30 sec. (Box 14, 1, a)
    - Vocal track for fotonovela 'DEEP END DANCE', performed by Robert Beltran and Teri Nogales. Written by Gamboa. Originally presented at U.C.L.A. Images from this fotonovela appear in GAMBOA SLIDES #111-116. 1982. 4 min. 30 sec. (Box 14, 1, b)
    - Vocal track for fotonovela "BIITER PILLOW', performed by Marisela Norte and Gronk. Written by Gamboa. Originally presented at U.C.L.A. 1982. 4 min. 30 sec.. (Box 14, 1, c)
    - CLUB LIMBO, Story #4 of 4 by Gamboa. performed by Gamboa. (See slide list description for slide #117-119. also clippings and manuscripts for CLUB LIMBO). 1989. 10 min. (Box 14, 1, d)
    - Gallery Talk by Gamboa at LA JOLLA MUSEUM. Oct 25, 1988. 24 min. (cont'd) (Box 14, 1, e)
    - (cont'd) Gallery Talk by Gamboa at LA JOLLA MUSEUM. 20 min. (Box 14, 1, f)
    - Random interviews at opening reception for exhibition ILLEGAL LANDSCAPE exhibition, works by Herron/Gronk at Cal State U.L.A. interviews by Gamboa. Dec 3. 1980. 19 min. (Box 14, 1, g)
    - John Valadez, artist, interviewed by Gamboa. Oct 16, 1987. 5 min. (Box 14, 1, h)
  - Audio Tape 2
    - John Valadez interviewed by Gamboa. Nov 16, 1987. 45 min. (cont'd) (Box 14, 2, a)
    - (cont'd) John Valdez interviewed by Gamboa. Nov 16. 1987. 9 min (Box 14, 2, b)
    - LET'S RAP television show, KTTV, L.A. Alicia Sandoval interviews Gamboa. Recording from TV set in ELA. April. 1978. 12 min. (Box 14, 2, c)
    - Vocal track for fotonovela "DOOMESTIC LIFE"., performed by Barbara Carrasco, Daniel J. Martinez. and Diego Gamboa. Written by Gamboa. Originally presented at Al's Bar. Image from this fotonovela appears in GAMBOA SLIDE #121. 1986. 4 min. (Box 14, 2, d)
    - Random interviews at opening reception for exhibition MURALS OF AZTLAN at Craft and Folk Art Museum, L.A. Interviews by Gamboa. June 2. 1981. 9 min. (Box 14, 2, e)
    - Telephone interview with Carlos Almaraz, artist, by Gamboa. June 1, 1981. 2 min. (radio station interference during this telephone conversation.) (Box 14, 2, f)
    - John Valdez interviewed by Gamboa. June 6. 1981. 2 min. (Box 14, 2, g)
    - ANTIZONA. Vocal track for fotonovela segment of performance, performed by George Silva. Image from this fotonovela appears in GAMBOA SLIDE #126 also (see slide list #126 for description). 1987. 2 min. (Box 14, 2, h)
    - Telephone message for Gamboa from: Cyclona. Nov 19. 1994. (Box 14, 2, i)
  - Audio Tape 3
    - Telephone interview with Willie Herron by Gamboa. June 6, 1981. 18 min. (radio station interference.) (Box 14, 3, a)
    - Vocal track for fotonovela "DON'T NOT", performed by Humberto Sandoval and Lorraine Ordaz. Images/description appear in GAMBOA SLIDES #66-#74. originally presented at Galeria de la Raza. 1984. 5 min. (Box 14, 3, b)
    - Vocal track for fotonovela "X's PARTY", performed by Therese Covarrubias and Gamboa (as replacement for Daniel Villarreal). Images/description appear in GAMBOA SLIDES #91-#98. Originally presented at UC Santa Cruz. 1983. 4 min. (Box 14, 3, c)
    - Audio track for fotonovela "TEMPLE OF THE ANONYMOUS", performed by Sean Carrillo. Originally performed at Galeria de la Raza. 1984. 2 min. (Box 14, 3, d)
    - Radio drama ORPHANS OF MODERNISM, II. Written/directed by Gamboa. KPFX FM, L.A. broadcast, April 3, 1984. 14 min. (Box 14, 3, e)
    - CLUB LIMBO. Live performance by Max Benavidez and Gamboa. (see clippings). 1989. 9 min. (Box 14, 3, f)
    - CLUB LIMBO, Story #3 of 4 by Gamboa, Performed by Alberto Ybarra, Anthony C. Sandoval, and Frances Salome España. 1989. 15 min. (Box 14, 3, g)
    - Message: Gronk. Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, h)
    - Message: Diane Gamboa, Mar 1987. (Box 14, 3, i)
    - Message: Gronk. Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, j)
    - Message: Gronk, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, k)
    - Message: Arthur Marchand, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, l)
    - Message: Marcos Sanchez, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, m)
    - Message: Jo Ann Pottlitzer, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, n)
    - Message: Diane Gamboa, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, o)
    - Message: Gronk, 1987 (Box 14, 3, p)
    - Message: Gronk. Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, q)
    - Message: Diane Gamboa, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, r)
    - Message: Diane Gamboa, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, s)
    - Message: Diane Gamboa, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, t)
    - Message: Daniel J. Martinez. Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, u)
    - Message: Jesus Treviño, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, v)
    - Message: John Valadez, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, w)
    - Message: Max Benavidez, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, x)
    - Message: Daniel J. Martinez, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, y)
    - Juan Garza and Rene Yañez, Mar 1987 (Box 14, 3, z)
    - KPFK radio broadcast interview of Willie Herron. June 8, 1975. 2 min. (Box 14, 3, aa)
    - THE UNDERTAKERS, "DRUG CITY". 1981. 2 min (Box 14, 3, bb)
    - THE UNDERTAKERS, "NO PAIN". 1981. 2 min (Box 14, 3, cc)
    - THE UNDERTAKERS, "SITUATION'S GETTING BAD", 1981. 2 min (Box 14, 3, dd)
  - Audio Tape 4
    - Barbara Carrasco, artist, interviewed by Gamboa. Nov 23, 1982. 45 min. (cont'd) (Box 14, 4, a)
    - (cont'd) Barbara Carrasco interviewed by Gamboa. Nov 23, 1982. 2 min. (Box 14, 4, b)
    - Gronk, artist, interviewed by Gamboa. Oct 25, 1986. 30 min.. (Box 14, 4, c)
    - Message: Patssi, Feb 1985 (Box 14, 4, d)
    - Message: Patssi, Feb, 1985 (Box 14, 4, e)
    - Message: Humberto Sandoval, Feb 1985 (Box 14, 4, f)
    - Message: Gronk, Feb 1985 (Box 14, 4, g)
    - Message: Jeff Huereque, Feb 1985 (Box 14, 4, h)
    - Arthur Marchand, May 1987 (Box 14, 4, i)
    - Gallery Talk by John Valadez. May 1987. 5 min. (Box 14, 4, j)
    - Message: Richard Montoya, May 1987 (Box 14, 4, k)
    - Message: Patssi 1987 (Box 14, 4, 1)
    - Message: Anonymous, 1986 (Box 14, 4, m)
    - Message: Gronk, Sept 1986 (Box 14, 4, n)
    - Message: Anonymous, Sept 1986 (Box 14, 4, o)
    - Willie Herron, artist, interviewed by Max Benavidez. KPFK-FM radio broadcast. Aug 31, 1981. 5 min. (Box 14, 4, p)
  - Audio Tape 5
    - CLUB LIMBO. Story #1 of 4 by Gamboa, performed by Diego Gamboa and Ricardo Gonzalves. (see GAMBOA SLIDE LIST #122-#123). 1989. 15 min. (Box 14, 5, a)
    - Gamboa lecture at UCLA symposium ARTS & HISTORY RECONSIDERED, Mar 8. 1986. 15 min. (Box 14, 5, b)
    - John Valdez (with Gronk present) interviewed by Gamboa. Clifton's cafeteria, L.A., Feb 23, 1983. 15 min. (cont'd) (Box 14, 5, c)
    - (cont'd)-John Valadez interviewed by Gamboa. Feb 23, 1983. 33 min. (Box 14, 5, d)
    - John Valdez interviewed by Gamboa. Clifton's cafeteria, L.A. Jan 25. 1984. 12 min. (Box 14, 5, e)
  - Audio Tape 6
    - Anonymous: May, 1985 (Box 14, 6, a)
    - Anonymous: May, 1985 (Box 14, 6, b)
    - Anonymous: May, 1985 (Box 14, 6, c)
    - Galeria Posada, May 1985 (Box 14, 6, d)
    - Humberto Sandoval, May 1985 (Box 14, 6, e)
    - Gronk, May 1985 (Box 14, 6, f)
    - Patssi, May 1985 (Box 14, 6, g)
    - Juan Garza, May 1985 (Box 14, 6, h)
    - Gronk, May 1985 (Box 14, 6, i)
    - Max Benavidez, May 1985 (Box 14, 6, j)
    - Gronk, May 1985 (Box 14, 6, k)
    - Patssi, May 1985 (Box 14, 6, 1)
    - Anonymous, May 1985 (Box 14, 6, m)
    - Guillermo Gomez Peña, June 1985 (Box 14, 6, n)
    - Gronk, June 1985 (Box 14, 6, o)
    - Gronk, June 1985 (Box 14, 6, p)
    - Gronk, June 1985 (Box 14, 6, q)
    - Anonymous, June 1985 (Box 14, 6, r)
    - Guillermo Gomez Peña, Aug 1985 (Box 14, 6, s)
    - Jesus Treviño, 1985 (Box 14, 6, t)
    - Daniel J. Martinez. Aug 1985 (Box 14, 6, u)
    - Daniel J. Martinez artist, interviewed by Gamboa. Oct 27. 1986. 35 min. (Box 14, 6, v)
    - Diane Gamboa, artist, interviewed by Harry Gamboa Jr. Oct 27, 1986. 6 min. (cont'd) (Box 14, 6, w)
    - (cont'd) Diane interviewed by Harry Gamboa Jr. Oct 27, 1986. 21 min (Box 14, 6, x)
    - Message: Gerardo Velazquez, Dec 1984 (Box 14, 6, y)
    - Message: Gerardo Velazquez, Dec 1984 (Box 14, 6, z)
    - Message: Gronk, 1984 (Box 14, 6, aa)
    - Message: Ruben Guevara, 1984 (Box 14, 6, bb)
    - Message: Barbara Carrasco, Dec 1984 (Box 14, 6, cc)
    - Message: Gronk. Dec 1984 (Box 14, 6, dd)
    - Message: Patssi, Dec 1985 (Box 14, 6, ee)
    - Message: Gronk, Dec 1985 (Box 14, 6, ff)
    - Message: Rene Yañez, Nov 1986 (Box 14, 6, gg)
    - Message: Max Benavidez. Dec 1987 (Box 14, 6, hh)
    - Message: David Avalos, Dec 1987 (Box 14, 6, ii)
    - Message: Yreina cervantez. Dec 1987 (Box 14, 6, jj)
    - Message: Zaneta Vargas, Nov 1984 (Box 14, 6, kk)
    - Message: Barbara Carrasco, Nov 1984 (Box 14, 6, ll)
    - Message: Carmen Gamboa. Nov 1984 (Box 14, 6, mm)
    - Message: Gronk. Dec 1984 (Box 14, 6, nn)
    - Message: Arthur Marchand, Dec 1984 (Box 14, 6, oo)
    - Message: Rosalio Muñoz, Sept 1989 (Box 14, 6, pp)
    - Message: Gronk. June 1985 (Box 14, 6, qq)
    - Message: Armando Cristeto, June 1985 (Box 14, 6, rr)
    - Message: Gronk. July 1985 (Box 14, 6, ss)
    - Message: Patssi, July 1985 (Box 14, 6, tt)
    - Message:Juan Garza, July 1985 (Box 14, 6, uu)
    - Message: Daniel J. Martinez, Oct 1984 (Box 14, 6, vv)
    - Message: Ricardo Valverde. Apr 1985 (Box 14, 6, ww)
    - Anonymous, Apr 1985 (Box 14, 6, xx)
    - Anonymous, Apr 1985 (Box 14, 6, yy)
    - Anonymous, Apr 1985 (Box 14, 6, zz)
    - Anonymous, Apr 1985 (Box 14, 6, aaa)
    - Marcos Sanchez. Jan 1986 (Box 14, 6, bbb)
    - Message: Helena Viramontes, Jan 1986 (Box 14, 6, ccc)
    - Message: Robert Buitron, Feb 1986 (Box 14, 6, ddd)
    - Message: Linda Gamboa, Feb 1986 (Box 14, 6, eee)
    - Message: Barbara Carrasco, Feb 1986 (Box 14, 6, fff)
    - Message: Harry T. Gamboa, Feb 1986 (Box 14, 6, ggg)
    - Message: Eloy Rodriguez, Feb 19B6 (Box 14, 6, hhh)
    - Message: Barbara Carrasco, Feb 1986 (Box 14, 6, iii)
    - Message: Daniel J. Martinez, Feb 1986 (Box 14, 6, jjj)
    - Message: Max Benavidez, Feb 1986 (Box 14, 6, kkk)
    - Message: Gronk, Feb 1986 (Box 14, 6, lll)
    - Message: John Valadez. Feb 1986 (Box 14, 6, mmm)
    - Message: Anonymous. Nov 1985 (Box 14, 6, nnn)
    - Message: Anonymous. Nov 1985 (Box 14, 6, ooo)
    - Message: Arthur Marchand, Nov 1985 (Box 14, 6, ppp)
    - Message: Ralph Cordova, Jan 1987 (Box 14, 6, qqq)
    - Message: Eloy Rodriguez, Jan 1987 (Box 14, 6, rrr)
    - Message: Guillermo Gomez Peña, Jan 1987 (Box 14, 6, sss)
  - Audio Tape 7
    - Humberto Sandoval, performer, interviewed by Gamboa. L.A., April 22, 1995. 45 min. (cont'd) (Box 14, 7, a)
    - (cont'd) Humberto Sandoval interviewed by April 22, 1995. 45 min. (Box 14, 7, b)
  - Audio Tape 8
    - Max Benavidez, poet/performer, interviewed by Gamboa. L.A,, April 22. 1995. 45 min. (cont'd) (Box 14, 8, a)
    - (cont'd) Max Benavidez interviewed by Gamboa. April 22, 1995. 28 min. (Box 14, 8, b)
    - Message: Daniel J. Martinez, April 1986 (Box 14, 8, c)
    - Message: Marcos Sanchez, April 1986 (Box 14, 8, d)
    - Message: Diane Gamboa, April 1986 (Box 14, 8, e)
    - Message: Diego Gamboa, April 1986 (Box 14, 8, f)
    - Message: George Silva. April 1986 (Box 14, 8, g)
    - Message: Armando Rascon, Nov 1987 (Box 14, 8, h)
    - Message: Dana Friis Hansen, Nov 1987 (Box 14, 8, i)
    - Message: Diane Gamboa. Mar 1986 (Box 14, 8, J)
    - Message: Harry T. a, Mar 1986 (Box 14, 8, k)
    - John Valadez, artist, interviewed by Gamboa. L.A., Feb 10, 1983. 12 min. (Box 14, 8, 1)
  - Audio Tape 9
    - Barbara Carrasco, artist, interviewed by Gamboa. Oct 30, 1986. 28 min. (Box 14, 9, a)
    - Message: Daniel J. Martinez, June 1986 (Box 14, 9, b)
    - Message: Daniel J. Martinez, June 1986 (Box 14, 9, c)
    - Message: Marcos Sanchez, June 1986 (Box 14, 9, d)
    - Message: Barbara Carrasco, July 1986 (Box 14, 9, e)
    - Harry Gamboa Jr. as panelist for "CHICANO CODICES" exhibition at The Mexican Museum, San Francisco. 1992. 10 min. (Box 14, 9, f)
    - Therese Covarrubias and THE BRAT, "STARRY NIGHT", 1984. 3 min. (Box 14, 9, g)
    - Message: Diego Gamboa, May 1988 (Box 14, 9, h)
    - Message: Rudy Guglielmo, May 1988 (Box 14, 9, i)
    - Message: Magu Lujan, May 1988 (Box 14, 9, j)
    - Message: Zaneta Vargas, May 1988 (Box 14, 9, k)
    - Artist statement by Gamboa. L.A., April 23, 1995. 45 min. (Box 14, 9, l)
- Series XII: Video Tape Listing
  - Video Tape 1
    - L.A. Merge, 1990 Color/Mono 12 min. Diego Gamboa. Humberto Sandoval. & Barbara Carrasco provide testimony about life on the freeways of L.A. (Box 15, 1, a)
    - L.A. History: A Mexican Perspective, Mural by Barbara Carrasco. Color/Mono 10 min. (rough edit) The 16' x 80' mural is prepared by Barbara Carrasco for its 3 week exhibition at Union Station as part of the 1990 L.A. Festival. The opening reception is attended by various Chicano artists. (Box 15, 1, b)
    - Vis-A-vid, 1992 color/stereo 13 min. Host Ralph Cordova presents 3 vignettes: "COLD JAVA", performed by Max Benavidez; DISCONNECTED, performed by Barbara Carrasco; and "FAST LANE", performed by Diego Gamboa. Writer/Director: Harry Gamboa Jr. Vis-A-Vid awarded Premio Mesquite, 1992 San Antonio CineFestival. (Box 15, 1, c)
    - Retain Retake, 1992 Color/Stereo 11 min. Harry T. Gamboa and Carmen Gamboa reminisce and comment on current life as they look through a family photo album. (Box 15, 1, d)
    - Fire Medicine, 1992 Color/Stereo 12 min. Various individuals relate experiences pertaining to the use and consumption of chiles. Music: Jose Montoya, Larry Yañez, and Gerardo Velazquez Director: Harry Gamboa, Jr. (Box 15, 1, e)
  - Video Tape 2
    - Problems in the History of Chicano Art, W93, UCSB, 1993 Color/Stereo 1 hour, 24 min. Students create/present their views in class for video. Instructor/Video:Harry Gamboa Jr. (Box 15, 2, a)
  - Video Tape 3
    - Baby Kake, 1985 Color/Mono 6 min. Mother (Barbara Carrasco) is struggling to raise Baby (Humberto Sandoval) during the absence/presence of Father (Gronk) as Marie Antionette (Ruben Zamora) provides guidance. Synthesized music: Gerardo Velazquez Writer/Director: Harry Gamboa Jr. (Box 15, 3, a)
    - Blanx, 1984 BW/Mono 7 min. A possessive relationship loses its grip. Performed by Lorraine Ordaz and Gronk. Synthesized music: Gerardo Velazquez Writer/Director: Harry Gamboa Jr. (Box 15, 3, b)
    - Vaporz, 1984 Color/Mono 7 min. An aimless/compulsive relationship leads to the silent treatment between Him (Juan Garza) and Her (Linda Gamboa). Silence is broken by Cousin Zombino (Humberto Sandoval). Synthesized music: Gerardo Velazquez Writer/Director: Harry Gamboa Jr. (Box 15, 3, c)
    - Sr. Tereshkova, 1974 BW Super-B Film (Video Transfer)/Silent 10 min. Sr. Tereshkova (Humberto Sandoval) dreams about earlier days and his victims (Patssi Valdez, Gronk, and Willie Herron). The nightmare isn't over until it's over. Writer/Director: Humberto Sandoval. Camera: Harry Gamboa Jr. (Box 15, 3, d)
    - Asco 72-74, 1974 BW Super-8 Film (Video Transfer)/Silent 10 min. Various Asco performances including Instant Mural & First Supper Willie Herron, Humberto Sandoval, Patssi Valdez & Gronk. Camera/Edit: Harry Gamboa Jr. (Box 15, 3, e)
    - No Supper, 1987 Color/Stereo. 19 min. Dad (Humberto Sandoval), Mom (Barbara Carrasco), and Son (Diego Gamboa) provide a minimalist venture into pseudodomestic life. Hosted by Max Benavidez. Synthesized music: Gerardo Velazquez Title Graphic: John Valadez. Set Graphics: Diane Gamboa. Writer/Director:Harry Gamboa Jr. (Box 15, 3, f)
  - Video Tape 4
    - L.A. Familia, 1993 Color/Stereo. 37 min. The Chicano nuclear family, Dad (Humberto Sandoval), Mom (Barbara Carrasco), and Son (Diego a) struggle to survive the emotional implosions and urban fallout. Director: Harry Gamboa Jr. L.A. Familia exhibited in 1993 at The Museum of Modern Art (NY) and included in the "1995 Biennial Exhibition" at the Whitney Museum of American Art (NY). (Box 15, 4, a)
  - Video Tape 5
    - Mañanamania, 1994 Color/Stereo. 13 min. Linda Gamboa bakes her cake and eats it too! Director: Harry Gamboa Jr. Mañanamania exhibited in 1994 at the Museum of Modern Art (NY). (Box 15, 5, a)
  - Video Tape 6
    - Fire Ants For Nothing, 1994 Color/Stereo 8 min. A homeless man proclaims his own humanity vs. futility. Performed by Ruben Guevara. Director: Harry Gamboa Jr. Fire Ants For Nothing, exhibited in THE URBAN DESERT, 1994. (Box 15, 6, a)
  - Video Tape 7
    - No Detour (a fotonovela), 1993 Color/Stereo 11 min. Three vignettes hit gridlock with performances by John Valadez. Maria Elena Chavez, Octavio Tizoc Gaitan-Diaz, and Max Benavidez. Director: Harry Gamboa Jr. (Box 15, 7, a)
    - Documentary Video, 1993 Color/Stereo 3 min. Intro & Outro to no documentary video. (Box 15, 7, b)
    - El Mundo L.A.: Humberto Sandoval, Actor, 1992 Color/Stereo 11 min. Sandoval presents his reality. (Box 15, 7, c)
    - El Mundo L.A.: David Avalos. Artist, 1992 Color/Stereo. 5 min. Avalos presents his reality. (Box 15, 7, d)
    - El Mundo L.A.: Max Benavidez. Writer, 1992 Color/Stereo. Benavidez presents his reality. 8 min. (Box 15, 7, e)
    - El Mundo L.A.: Rene Yañez, Artist/Curator, 1992. Color/Stereo. 9 min. Yañez presents his reality. (Box 15, 7, f)
    - El Mundo L.A.: Zaragosa Vargas. Ph.D., Historian, 1993. Color/Stereo 8 min. Vargas presents his reality. (Box 15, 7, g)
    - El Mundo L.A.: Raul Villa. Professor, 1993 Color/Stereo 8 min. Villa presents his reality. (Box 15, 7, h)
  - Video Tape 8
    The videos in Video tape #8 directed by Harry Gamboa Jr. and were presented in THE URBAN DESERT. 1994.
    - Loner With A Gun. 1994 Color/Stereo 5 min. An artist(Luis Becerra) paints the town with reminders of violence. (Box 15, 8, a)
    - At Fault. 1994 color/Stereo 6 min. Ex-spouses (Max Benavidez and Paulina Sahgun) meet in anger. (Box 15, 8, b)
    - Huevitos. 1994 color/Stereo. 20 min. Domestic life is hell when. Husband (Humberto Sandoval) and Wife (Barbara Carrasco) disagree about what is sunny-side-up. (Box 15, 8, c)
    - Eliminate The Sky, 1994 Color/Stereo 13 min. Two women (Diane Gamboa and Kate Vozoff) attempt to save/salvage a young man (Anthony C. Sandoval) whose idealism has taken him over the edge. (Box 15, 8, d)
    - CUP of Sand, 1994 Color/Stereo 8 min. Roberto Bedoya's cup does not runneth over. Title Graphics: Zaneta Kosiba Vargas (Box 15, 8, e)